Guide to the Carl Gustav Hempel Papers, 1903-1997 ASP.1999.01
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Carl Gustav Hempel Papers
1903-1997
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Hempel, Carl G. (Carl Gustav)
ASP.1999.01
25 Linear Feet
Carl Gustav Hempel was a philosopher of science who played a central role in the development of logical positivism. His work is primarily associated with the concept of deductive-nomological explanation and with the Raven paradox. The papers include biographical material, correspondence, research and lecture manuscripts, teaching documents, and offprints by him and others, mostly stemming from his post-immigration period in the U.S. Digital reproductions of this collection are available online.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of this collection are available online.
Biography
Carl Gustav Hempel was born in 1905 in Oranienburg, Germany. He studied mathematics, physics, and philosophy at the Universities of Göttingen, Heidelberg, Berlin, and Vienna. In 1929, he participated in a congress on scientific philosophy where he met Rudolf Carnap. Inspired by Carnap's work, Hempel moved to Vienna during the winter semester of 1929-1930 and joined in the meetings of the Vienna Circle. After returning to Berlin, he earned his Ph.D. in 1934 for his work on probability under Hans Reichenbach, himself a major figure in the field of logical empiricism. The same year, Hempel and his first wife Eva left the increasingly repressive Germany and emigrated to Belgium, with the help of Paul Oppenheim, with whom he co-authored the book Der Typusbegriff im Lichte der neuen Logik in 1936. After three years of private research and writing, Hempel emigrated to the U.S. in 1937, accepting a position as Carnap's research assistant in philosophy at the University of Chicago. Subsequently, he held positions at the City College of New York, Queens College, and Yale University, where he was promoted to the rank of Professor in 1953. During his Yale period, Hempel also spent a semester as a Visiting Professor at Columbia University in the fall of 1950, as a Hibben Research Fellow at Princeton in the spring of 1953, and a year as a Visiting Professor at Harvard University in 1953-1954. In 1955, Hempel joined the Princeton faculty as a Stuart Professor of Philosophy. He came to the University of Pittsburgh in 1976 as a University Professor of Philosophy and stayed until 1985, when he returned to Princeton. On November 9, 1997, Hempel died at age 92 near his home in Princeton Township, New Jersey.
Hempel was a philosopher of science who played a central role in the development of logical positivism or logical empiricism. In his early years, he was a member of the so called Berlin Circle ("Gesellschaft für wissenschaftliche Philosophie"), a Berlin counterpart to the Vienna Circle. Hempel's work is mainly associated with the concept of deductive-nomological explanation and with the Raven paradox. In 1948, Hempel developed with Paul Oppenheim a logically precise theory known as the Deductive-Nomological, or Covering Law, Model of Explanation, which sees scientific laws and theories as systematizing otherwise unwieldy bodies of particular empirical claims. To deal with probabilistic explanation, Hempel articulated an Inductive-Statistical Model in 1962. He also developed models of historical and functional explanation in the biological and social sciences, as well as of historical explanation. Those models shaped all subsequent work on scientific explanation.
Hempel also sought to describe the conditions under which particular reports of observation may be said to confirm general hypothesis. His famous Raven Paradox exemplifies the logical challenge: Since the hypothesis (1) "All ravens are black" can be reformulated equivalently as (2) "All non-black things are non-ravens," the report of non-black non-ravens (e.g., white shoes) would seem to confirm (1) just as would the report of black ravens. Hempel then proposed a quantitative method for determining the degree of confirmation of any hypothesis by particular statements of evidence.
Hempel was author of the influential books Aspects of Scientific Explanation and Other Essays in the Philosophy of Science and Philosophy of Natural Science, which have been translated into ten languages. He held Guggenheim and Fulbright fellowships and served as a fellow at the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences at Stanford and as an honorary research fellow in philosophy at University College, London. He also was a fellow of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, a member of the Académie Internationale de Philosophie des Sciences and American Philosophical Society, and a corresponding fellow of the British Academy.
Scope and Content Notes
The papers originate from Hempel's office at Princeton University. The majority of the material was organized by Hempel according to various filing systems. Whenever possible, the original order has been maintained. The greater part of the papers is in English, but a considerable amount is also in German, and a few items are in French. The papers feature some early, pre-immigration material from Hempel's European period while living in Berlin, Vienna, and Brussels. The majority of the documents, however, stem from his post-immigration period in the U.S. The papers are divided into five series. Hempel's biographical material covers mainly the years 1928 to 1966 and comprises personal and educational records, such as diaries, notebooks, diplomas, and professional records, e.g. curricula vitae and employment correspondence. The correspondence series extends from the 1920s to the 1990s, with the bulk of the material concentrating on the years 1940-1990. The correspondence is subdivided into general correspondence; exchanges between Hempel, Paul Oppenheim, and Kurt Grelling; contacts between Hempel, Oppenheim, and other correspondents; family correspondence; and letters of recommendation, which are currently closed to research access. Documents in the research, lectures and publications series consist of Hempel's research manuscripts and notes, lecture drafts, book inserts, and a variety of material pertaining to his conference participations, contributions, and publications, generally focusing on the years 1950 to 1990. Manuscripts on both the Carus and Gavin David Young lectures are contained in two separate subseries. Hempel's teaching materials include folders he prepared for his graduate and undergraduate classes, in particular at the Universities of Yale, Princeton, and Pittsburgh, mostly covering the years 1949-1985. It also features a few dissertations and administrative documents. Please note that due to the sensitive and confidential nature of some of the material, access to this series is restricted. Finally, the offprints series is divided into offprints authored by Hempel and offprints authored by others. Offprints of others' publications are organized from A-Z according to author. Most of them contain handwritten annotations and dedications to Hempel, and some prominent authors in the field are featured.
Arrangement
Some series are divided into subseries. More detailed scope and content notes are available at the series level:
Series I. Biographical Material
Series II. Correspondence
Series III. Research, Lectures, and Publications
Series IV. Teaching
Series V. Audio Recordings
Series VI. Offprints
Access Restrictions
Access to the collection is open for research with the following exceptions: Letters of recommendation and some individual files in the general correspondence series are closed. Research access to material in the teaching series and to some files of correspondence is restricted; requests are subject to individual review by curator. Please contact the Archives & Special Collections for additional information.
Acquisition Information
The papers were purchased and received in one accession in July 1999 from Hempel's wife, Diane Hempel.
Previous Citation
Carl Gustav Hempel Papers, 1903-1997, ASP.1999.01, Archives of Scientific Philosophy, Special Collections Department, University of Pittsburgh
Science -- Philosophy -- History -- 20th century; Science -- Philosophy -- History -- Sources; Knowledge, Theory of -- History -- 20th century; Explanation; Analysis (Philosophy); Science -- Methodology; Vienna circle; Personal correspondence; Lecture notes; Manuscripts for publication; Offprints; Diaries; Logical positivism -- History -- 20th century; Philosophy; Grelling, Kurt; Oppenheim, Paul; Princeton University -- Faculty; University of Pittsburgh -- Faculty; Yale University -- Faculty; Reichenbach, Hans; Hempel, Carl G. (Carl Gustav) -- Archives; Carnap, Rudolf, 1891-1970; Becker-Freyseng, Albrecht; Feigl, Herbert
- Biographical Material, 1903-1991; I.
  Scope and Contents note
  This series is divided into two subseries representing Hempel's personal, educational, and professional records.
  - Personal and Educational Records, 1903-1991; 1.
    Hempel's personal and educational records (subseries 1) feature a few family items, some documents on his and his first wife Eva's immigration to the U.S., educational documents and certificates such as diplomas and certificates of his high school graduation and teacher certification; his class registrations at the Universities of Göttingen (1923-1924), Heidelberg (1924), Berlin (1924-1928), and Vienna (1929-1930). Included are also student notes on seminars and discussions that cover mostly courses he took with Carnap at the University of Chicago during the years 1937-1939 and his diaries from 1939 to 1966, with some gaps.
    - Family Documents, 1903-1905 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Educational Diplomas and Certificates, 1923-1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Immigration Documents, 1938-1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Seminar Notes Köhler: Ein altes Scheinproblem, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Seminar Notes Carnap: Research Seminar & Semantik [sic] Meeting, Fall 1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Seminar Notes Carnap: Discussion Group, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Seminar Notes Carnap: Logistik, Fall 1937, Winter 1937-1938, University of Chicago (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Seminar Notes Carnap: Analytic Method in Philosophy (Course 331), Spring Quarter 1938 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Seminar Notes Carnap: Research Seminar Problems in the Logical Foundation of Mathematics, Winter 1938 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Seminar Notes Carnap: Semantics, Spring 1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Seminar Notes Carnap: Advanced Logical Syntax, Spring Term 1939 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Notes on Carnap, Santa Fe, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Two Seminars by Tarski: 1. Syntax of the Sentenial Calculus; 2. Problems of Completeness & Decidability, 1940-1941 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Handwritten Excerpt by Hempel from Tarski's "Fundamentale Begriffe der Methodologie der deduktiven Wissenschaften I.", 1936 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Unidentified Notes by Hempel, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Notes Discussion Group: Scientific Method Group (undated) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Diaries, 1939-1966 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence Journals, 1949-1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Expense Journal, 1948-1950 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Medical Reports [RESTRICTED], 1942-1958 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Interview of Hempel by Richard Nollan: First and Revised Copies and Related Correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Professional Records, 1930-1991; 2.
    His professional records (subseries 2) comprise several curricula vitae in German and English, a 1991 bibliography, biographical sketches; letters of reference, testimonials, and correspondence concerning Hempel's applications for academic positions in the U.S., e.g. as Carnap's research associate at the University of Chicago; and an exchange on his appointment to Yale University. Present are also items documenting Hempel's early professional and academic activities including annual activity reports and newspaper clippings on his public talks and appearances as well as on other events or individuals; statements and correspondence on research projects, grant applications, leave requests; and lecture photographs.
    - Curricula Vitae, Bibliographies, and Biographical Sketches, 1932-1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Employment Correspondence and Testimonials [RESTRICTED], 1936-1954 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Yale University: Annual Reports of the Department of Philosophy, 1948-1955 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Hempel's Annual Professional Activity Reports, 1950-1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Grants, Research Projects, Leave Requests, and Fellowships, 1952-1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Lecture Photographs, 1958-1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Permissions to Reprint from Hempel's Publications, 1978-1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence with Doctoral Candidates, 1962-1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Wissenschaftskolleg Berlin: Addresses and Information, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1930-1975 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Articles from the Times Literary Supplement, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Illustration by Unknown Author (Hansen?) and Unidentified Typescript, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Honarary Doctoral Degree Certificates, 1975-1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1924-1997; II.
  All correspondence is arranged alphabetically according to the personal or institutional name of the correspondent. Generally, each exchange contains correspondence between Hempel and the named individual or institution. Within each folder items are arranged chronologically with the most recent document first. This arrangement essentially follows Hempel's original filing system. In some instances, where the exchange consists of only a few items, one folder can comprise two or more correspondents, which is indicated by a range of names in the folder title instead of one single name. Please note that Hempel sometimes filed topical items within the correspondence series. In these cases, the topic (mostly conferences or events) is listed in the heading instead of a personal name. For example, material relating to Hempel's China lectures can be found both in the correspondence file under 'C' and in the series of Hempel's lectures. Please also note that some pieces of correspondence that are of confidential or sensitive nature are closed. This case will be indicated by the term 'closed' in square brackets following the folder heading.
  - General Correspondence, 1930-1996; 1.
    The general correspondence covers both personal and professional correspondence and involves individuals and institutions discussing professional, academic, as well as personal issues. Some exchanges are brief whereas others might extent over several folders, involving for the most part individuals Hempel stayed in close contact with throughout his life, e.g. his exchanges with Rudolf Carnap and Herbert Feigl; or they reflect close relationships during certain time periods, like his correspondence with Albrecht Becker-Freyseng during the late 1920s and early 1930s. The general correspondence illustrates furthermore Hempel's involvement in various projects, collaborations, and his affiliation with several institutions. Examples are substantial communications with the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences at Stanford, and with Wolfgang Essler documenting their collaboration on reviving and editing the journal Erkenntnis during the 1970s and 1980.
    - Aarsleff, Hans—Abel, Reuben, 1973 and 1980 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Academic Committee on Soviet Jewry, 1968-1976 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Académie Internationale de Philosophie des Sciences, 1965-1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Achinstein, Peter, 1961-1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Ackermann, Robert, 1962-1963 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Addis, Laird—Adibi, Elise, 1973-1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Agassi, Joseph, 1965-1988 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Agazzi, Evandro, 1971-1977 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Ahn, Wonyeong, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Ajdukiewicz, K., 1959-1961 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Albert, Hans—Almeder, Robert, 1960-1980 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - American Academy of Arts and Sciences (AAAS), 1957-1993 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - American Antiquity, 1969-1973 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - APA-Latin American Philosophers, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - American Philosophical Association, 1959-1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - American Philosophical Quarterly, 1962-1976 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - American Philosophical Society, 1966-1985 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - American Professors for Peace in the Middle East, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - American Psychological Association, 1969-1971 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Amherst College, 1981 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Amino, Leo and Julie, 1954 and 1979 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Anderson, Alan Ross, 1962-1974 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Anderssen, Bob—Aomi, Junichi, 1968-1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Appleton-Century-Crofts, Publisher, 1957-1967 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Archiv für Rechts- und Sozialphilosophie, 1965-1969 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Armstrong, James I. (Middlebury College), 1968 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Association for the Advancement of Philosophy and Psychiatry (Donald M. Mender), 1996 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Association for Symbolic Logic, 1962-1976 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Atlas, Jay D.—Austin, William H., 1960-1976 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Australia Universities: Canberra, Flinders, Latrobe, Melbourne, Monash, Sydney, and Wollongang, 1978-1982 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Australian National University (PhD exam Mills), 1963-1970 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Bahr, Walter, 1947-1982 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Baier, Kurt and Annette, 1987-1991 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Balkcom, John E.—Bar-eli, Gilad, 1961-1983 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Bar-Hillel, Yehoshua and Maya, 1950-1980 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Bar-Ilan University—Baumoh, Ellen, 1955-1977 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Bayerische Akademie der Wissenschaften, cross reference with Carl Freier von Siemens Stiftung, 1977-1980 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Baylis, Charles A.—Beard, Robert W., Florida State U., 1956-1957 and 1972 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Beardsley, Elizabeth and Monroe, 1954-1982 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Bechler, Zev—Beidler, Marsha W., 1976 and 1990 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Becker-Freyseng, Albrecht, 1930-1938, 1947, 1972-1976,and 1991 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Benacerraf, Paul, 1962-1985 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Benioff, Paul—Benjamin, A. Cornelius, 1955-1971 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Ben-Menahem, Yemima, 1986-1989 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Bennett, Michael R.—Benson, Arthur J., 1967-1979 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Bergmann, Gustav, 1950-1956 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Berka, Karel, 1971 and 1972 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Berlin-Brandenburgische Akademie der Wissenschaften, 1996 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Bernays, Paul, 1956-1965 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Bernstein, Richard, 1955-1967 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Bertalanffy, L. von, 1950-1954 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Beth, E.M.—Birnbaum, Allen, 1958-1987 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Black, Max (and Philosophy Review), 1954-1972 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Blake, James J., 1974-1981 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Blanshard, Brand, 1951-1975 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Block, Ned, 1977-1979 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Blum, Harold F., 1962-1968 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Bobbs-Merrill Publishing Co., 1965-1974 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Bochner, Sal, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Bohnert, Herbert, 1949-1982 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Bologna Ceremony 1989: Correspondence with Maria Carla Galvotti, Invitation and Acceptance, incl. Photographs, 1989 and 1990 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Bonevac, Daniel—Bowles, George, 1979-1985 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Bowman-Saadé, Sylvia—Boylan, Michael, 1971-1982 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Braithwaite, R.B., 1959 and 1960 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Brandeis University, 1959-1974 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Brandt, Richard (Swarthmore College), 1951-1967 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Braude, Ben B., 1975 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Braun, Joachim, 1972 and 1976 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Braybrooke, David, 1961-1979 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Brennan, Penny, 1975-1987 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Bridgeman, Percy Williams Memorial Service Booklet, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - British Academy, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - British Museum, 1961 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - British Society for the Philosophy of Science & British Journal for the Philosophy of Science, 1966-1984 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Brizzio, R.A. De Lio de, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Brody, Baruch A., 1967-1979 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Bromberger, Sylvain, 1961-1969 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Brooklyn College, 1968-1969 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Brown, Arthur (Queens College), 1950 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Brown, John Howell—Brunner, Karl, 1958-1972 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Brunswik, Egon and Else Frenkel-Brunswik, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Brutian, George A.—Bulgarian Organizing Committee for the XVth World Congress of Philosophy, 1965-1972 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Bunge, Mario, 1958-1972 (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Bunn, Bill—Burnyeat, Myles, 1970-1983 (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Butler, Ronald J., 1958-1967 (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Bynam, Terry, 1967-1973 (Box 9, Folder 25)
      Conditions Governing Access note
      [CLOSED]
    - Cairns, Huntington—Camp, Joe, 1949-1984 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Canada Council, 1969-1971 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Carleton College, 1974-1976 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      [RESTRICTED]
    - Carleton College re. 1980 Meeting and 1981 Honorary Doctorate, 1979-1981 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Carnap, Rudolf, 1943-1953 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Carnap, Rudolf, 1954-1957 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Carnap, Rudolf, 1958-1961 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Carnap, Rudolf, 1962-1992 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Carnap, Rudolf & Ina with Paul Oppenheim, 1954-1959 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Carnap: Notes on Semantics, 1955 and Methodological Character of Theoretical Concepts, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Carnap Collection Committee, 1974-1983 (Box 11, Folder 07-08)
    - Carnegie Mellon Philosophy Club—Cartwright, Nancy, 1977-1992 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Carus Lectures, 1967-1970 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Cassirer, Eva, 1972-1991 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Castiglione, Robert L., 1981 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Catholic University of America, Washington Summer Institute, 1970-1973 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Cauman, Leigh S.—Center for Jewish Life, 1950-1982,and 1993 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, 1954-1979 (Box 12, Folder 07-08)
    - Chatalian, George—Chiaradia, Giovanni, 1967-1988 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - China Correspondence, 1979-1983 (Box 12, Folder 10-13)
    - Chinn, Ewing Y.—Church, Alonzo, 1946-1981 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Churchman, West C. (& Philosophy of Science), 1949-1958 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Cinncinnati, University of—Clark, Len, 1972-1982 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Clark, Peter, 1977-1984 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Clarkson, Geoffrey—Cobarrubias, Juan J. Gonzalez, 1962-1979 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Coffa, Alberto J., and Linda Wessels, 1969-1985 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Cohen, Jerry—Cohen, Julius, 1963-1981 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Cohen, Robert S., 1949-1983 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Cohn, Werner—Columbia University, 1950-1973 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Comey, David D.—Condon, E.U., 1957-1979 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Connecticut Academy of Arts and Sciences—Costatini, Domenico, 1952-1991 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Council for Philosophical Studies: Stanford '67 Correspondence with Shaffer etc., 1965-1970, 1982 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Craig, William, 1950-1958 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Creary, Lewis G., 1969 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Creath, Richard, 1979-1991 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Critchlow, Florence [Florence Gerhardt]—Chushing, James T., 1945-1990 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Dahl, Bob—Darlington, Jared, 1957-1992 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Dartmouth College, 1956-1979 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Davidson, Donald—Demos, Raphael, 1954-1991 (Box 14, Folder 5)